Finding Aid for Gerald R. Dunn papers, 1969-1984
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Gerald R. Dunn papers 1969-1984
Dunn, Gerald R.
861133 Aa 2
Regent of the University of Michigan. Topical files relating to his activities as a regent and the issues and problems affecting the University of Michigan.
7 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Gerald R. Dunn (donor no. 6374 )
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Gerald R. Dunn was regent of the University of Michigan from 1969 to 1985.
The Gerald R. Dunn collection consists of those materials accumulated as regent of the University of Michigan, 1969 to 1985. The files have been arranged into two alphabetical subseries: 1969-1976 files and 1977-1984 files. The files relate to such issues as affirmative action, the Black Action Movement, the discussion over the University's participation in DNA research, the development of the Flint and Dearborn campuses, student activism, and other issues during the presidencies of Robben W. Fleming and Harold Shapiro.
Subjects:
Affirmative action programs--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Black Action Movement (University of Michigan); Fleming, R. W. (Robben Wright), 1916-2010.; Shapiro, Harold T., 1935-; University of Michigan. Board of Regents.; University of Michigan--Dearborn.; University of Michigan--Flint.; University of Michigan--Research.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1961-1970.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1971-1980.
- Regental files
  - 1969-1976
    - Affirmative action (BAM strike) (Box 1)
    - Athletics (Box 1)
    - Butterfield Theatres (Box 1)
    - Classified Research (Box 1)
    - Dearborn (U-M) (Box 1)
    - Disabled students (Box 1)
    - DNA Research (Box 1)
    - Faculty service to outside parties (Box 1)
    - Finances (Box 1)
    - Financial assistance (Box 1)
    - Fleming, R.W. (Box 1)
    - Flint (U-M) (Box 1)
    - Flint (U-M) (Box 2)
    - Gerontology (Box 2)
    - Honorary degrees (Box 2)
    - Housing (Box 2)
    - Inquiries (Box 2)
    - Interlochen (Box 2)
    - Invitations (Box 2)
    - Labor (Box 2)
    - Medical Center (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 3)
    - Optometry (Box 3)
    - PIRGIM (Box 3)
    - Regents' retreats (Box 3)
    - ROTC (Box 3)
    - Salary (disclosure issue) (Box 3)
    - Student unrest (Box 3)
    - Sugar Island (Box 3)
    - Tuition (Box 3)
    - Veterans (Box 3)
    - Willow Run (Box 3)
  - 1977-1984
    (include some 1969-1976)
    - Academic Affairs (Box 3)
    - Affirmative Action (Box 3)
    - AGB (Box 3)
    - Alumni (Box 3)
    - Athletics (Box 3)
    - Budget Cutbacks (Box 3)
    - Butterfield (Box 3)
    - Capital Campaign (Box 3)
    - Correspondence 1979-1984 (Box 3)
    - Correspondence 1979-1984 (cont.) (Box 4)
    - Classified Research (Box 4)
    - U of M-Dearborn (Box 4)
    - Development Steering Committee (Box 4)
    - Disabled Students (Box 4)
    - Education (School of Education) (Box 4)
    - Finances (Box 4)
    - Financial Assistance (Box 4)
    - R. Fleming-(President) (Box 4)
    - Flint-U of M (Box 4)
    - High Technology Parks (Box 4)
    - HMO's (Box 4)
    - Honorary Degrees (Box 4)
    - Hospital (U of M) (Box 4)
    - Hospital (U of M) (cont.) (Box 5)
    - Housing (Box 5)
    - Inquiries (Box 5)
    - Investments (Box 5)
    - Labor (unions, GEO) (Box 5)
    - Legal Matters (lawsuits) (Box 5)
    - Medical School (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence March-November 1977 (Box 5)
    - Pirgim (Box 5)
    - Preferential Bidding (Box 5)
    - Recommendation Letters (Box 6)
    - Research and Reports (Box 6)
    - Review of Schools (Box 6)
    - R.O.T.C. (Box 6)
    - Salaries (Box 6)
    - President Harold Shapiro (Box 6)
    - Solomon Amendment (Box 6)
    - Student Code (Box 6)
    - Sugar Island (Box 6)
    - Tickets (Box 6)
    - Tuition (Box 6)
    - Divestment-South Africa (Box 6)
    - Divestment-South Africa (cont.) (Box 7)
    - State Supreme Court Cases (Box 7)
    - 1984 Re-election Campaign (Box 7)
    - Presidential Selection (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 7)